-♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ Way down in Deep 13
♪ Dr. Forrester and TV's Frank
♪ Were hatching an evil scheme
♪ They hired a temp
by the name of Mike ♪
♪ Just a regular Joe
they didn't like ♪
♪ Their experiment needed
a good test case ♪
♪ So they conked him
on the noggin ♪
♪ And they shot him into space
-Let me go!
-♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
-♪ La la la
-♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
-♪ La la la
-♪ Now, keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
-♪ La la la
-♪ He'll try to keep
his sanity ♪
♪ With the help
of his robot friends ♪
-Robot Roll Call.
-♪ Cambot
-Show yourself.
-♪ Gypsy
-I'm not ready.
-♪ Tom Servo
-Hello, there.
-♪ Crow
-That's one "O."
-♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
-♪ La la la
-Just repeat to yourself,
"It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax"
For "Mystery Science
Theater 3000"
[Doors thud and creak]
-Okay. You guys ready?
-Yes.
-Ready!
-♪ Oh, the yellow rose
of Texas ♪
-Hi, everyone. Welcome to
the Satellite of Love.
I'm Mike. This is Tom Servo,
and this is Crow T. Robot.
And we're just working on one
of those beloved old standards.
You know, these are
the kind of songs
that everyone can enjoy, and --
-Hey, hey, hey, Mike!
There's something coming in
on the Hexfield!
-Huh?
-Whoa!
-Hello? Yes?
-Yeah, hello, Arnie.
-Uh, Arnie?
-Arnie, you sound weird.
Look, you got to get over here
and sign these papers.
I know you're not thrilled
to hear from me.
-Uh, ma'am, I think you may
have the wrong number.
There's no Arnie here.
-Wow.
-[Whistles]
-That was weird. Well, let's go.-Okay.
-♪ Oh, the yellow rose
of Texas ♪
-Mike, uh, the Hexfield.
-Look, I know Arnie's there.
You don't got to cover
for him, Chopper.
Chopper, this is you, right?
Look, you don't have
to cover for him.
He just has to get over here
and sign these papers.
-Lady...
-Hold on.
What?
-What's for supper?
-Eggs.
-Again?
-Yes, again!
So is Arnie staying there
with you, Chopper?
-Uh, this may take a while.
We'll be right back.
-Look, Chop, do not let him
take advantage of you.
-Mom!
-He's a sweet guy...
-...but he takes,
takes, takes.
-Mom!
-Mommy's on the phone!
♪♪
-Of course I was only about 16when me and Arnie got hooked up.
Man, he was so good-looking
back then.
Nowadays, it's just
his whiskey breath, this dump,
and 4:00 a.m. calls
from the police.
Oh, hold on.
My bacon's on fire.
-Whew.
-Wow.
-Well, you know, she did have
a certain je ne sais quoi
about her, didn't she?
-No.
Let's see what
Benny and June are doing.
-Hello, Murray, automata.
Say, what's one of the most
popular forms of exercise
this month, hmm?
Hmm?
Well, that's right,
the recumbent bike.
As I see it,
recumbent creators were afraid
to make them too comfortable.
Well, I'm not afraid!
Ta-da, the recomfy bike!
[Laughs]
-Dr. F, could you tuck me in
before my ride?
-Of course, Franklin.
There you go.
Check out the reading lamp,
night stand,
and goose down comforter.
Of course, we may have to ditch
the wheels and the pedals
to make room for the ice machineand espresso bar, but...
-Uh, Doctor,
I can't get it to go.
-Well, try harder, you load!
-But there's kind of
a lot of stuff here.
-[Whiny voice] "There's kind of
a lot of stuff here."
[Normal voice] Nappy time,
don't you think, Frank?
Back up to you, Margot.
-[Snoring]
-Well, that is really,
really useless.
[Laughter]
Anyway, our invention
pumps new life
into that age-old deck
of playing cards.
-Mm-hmm.
-Let's face it.
With 52 cards,there's only so much you can do.
-A jack, queen, king,
give me a break!
-Ah!
-That's why we came up with
our own new cards to sort of
spice things up a bit.
Mine is the 8 of Chris Lemmon,
son of the very talented
Jack Lemmon.
-Chris Lemmon?
-Yeah.
I just loved him in "Duet."
-Huh.
Well, my card is Todd,
just Todd.
Todd is helpful,
and Todd is there for you.
-Todd? Todd?
-Yeah.
-Well, is he --
What value is he?
Is he royalty, or what?
-[Laughing] Well, Todd doesn't
like to be pigeonholed.
He says the term "royalty" puts
limitations on your dreams.
-Well, okay, what happens ifI lay down an 8 of Chris Lemmon?
Who wins?
-Oh, no,
Todd says numerical values
are meaningless,
and he doesn't like
competition.
Actually, now that you bring
it up, Todd says your
Chris Lemmon card has issues
he needs to work through,
but with a little...
-Well, if it's okay with Todd,
why doesn't Crow go next?
What do you got, buddy?
-Oh, yes, yes!
My card is the...
[imitating trumpet sounding]
...Crow of diamonds!
Whoo!
Crow of diamonds.
-Crow, I think you missed the
whole point of this exercise.
-Huh?
-Well, Todd thinks it's okay.
-Todd...
-[Snoring]
[Gasps]
-[Laughs]
-[Gasps]
Enough of your
touchy-feely crap, Nelson.
Today's movie really gets going
about two minutes
before the closing credits.
It's another Bert I. Gordon
pain parade called
the "Beginning of the End,"
and I hope
you have health insurance.
[Chuckles]
[Giggles]
-On your left!
-And then later on,
Todd's gonna show me this
really great massage technique
and photos from his weekend
with Robert Fulghum, and...
[Alarm buzzing]Oh, Movie Sign.
-Oh, we got movie sign!
-Dog darn it.
-Whoa!
[Doors thud and creak]
-Hey, you know,
I've got a good place for Todd.
-Yeah!
-Oh, that's fine.
Okay.
-Boy, you're fickle.
-Looks like this is where
Ichabod Crane takes his dates.
-Ooh, and, you know,
it'd be sexy
until you think
it might be my parents!
Oh, my God!
-Oh!
-♪ Ask me why
-Hey, how does he sing
while he's kissing her?
Oh.
-♪ Never be afraid
-You taste like vinyl.
-Bet you anything there's going
to be a claw
hanging from their door handle.
-Yep.
-[High-pitched voice]
No, not there.
Yeah, that's it.
Oh, yeah, oh.
-[Screams]
-Don't give me a hickey!
-What? What? What?
-Huh.
-Oh.
-What?
-The beginning of
the end already?
-I don't --
-It just started!
-Ugh, ugh.
Neat.
And the June Taylor dancers!
-[Laughs] Ugh!
-Is this a flashback
to previous credits?
-Yeah.
-I wonder what that lady saw
when she screamed there.
-Lou Ferrigno?
-Maybe.
-Oh, stop it!
I'm getting nauseated!
-Maybe she saw Bigfoot.
-Bigfoot Pizza?
-No, I -- Well, maybe.
-Oh, I don't --
-Oh, could I get some Dramamine
for this credits sequence?
-You okay, buddy?
-Yeah, I think so.
-Please welcome your
New Richmond High School
Marching Band!
-[Laughs]
-Honey...
-Mike, I think I need a bucket!
[Gagging]
-Credit sick there.
-Hang in there. Hang in.
-[Groans] Oh, I'm okay.
-Put your head
between your knees.
-Okay.
-Don't slip.
-That feel better?
-Yeah, yeah.
-Wow.
-Oh.
-This is like
"Beginning of the End"
bold condensed font here, huh?
-Mm-hmm.
-Oh, no, oh...
[Retching]
-Honey, do you think
you could keep down
some 7-Up and soda crackers?
-No.
-Some lukewarm pork?
-[Gags]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-[Retching]
-One more time!
-♪ Ba-da-dum-da-dum-da
♪ Dun-dun-dun-dun-da ♪
-There's too many notes.
-So is something gonna happen?
-No. [Sighs]
-Huh.
-Folks, we'll start the movie
soon as our ride gets here.
-Man, that car radio
is loud, huh?
-You know, Bert I. sure doesn't
skimp on the opening.
-This is 254
on the Ludlow swing...
-And we're hopelessly lost.
-...reporting a 984-2.
We'll be checking in
in 45 minutes.
-Ten-four, car 254, KLP-646.
-You want to say hi
to headquarters?
-Pull over.
I saw something.
-If they had to pull over
every time you see something,
it's going to be a long ride.
-Mantul is only five miles away.Yesterday, it was 10 miles away!
-Someone's moving the sign.
-Hmm.
[Dramatic chord strikes]
-Whoa.
-Something happened
off-screen here!
-Uh, Miss Mansfield?
-I'll report in.
-Oh.
-You know, these things just
don't do anything to me
emotionally anymore.
I'm drained.
-Hi. Me again.
-Car 254 to Champaign-Urbana.
-Urbana to 254, go ahead.
-Car 254 to Urbana.
We're investigating an accident
at junction 45
and Ludlow cutoff.
Foul play suspected.
-No, duh.
-Send homicide detail.
-Uh, hold on.
I'm going to read you a poem.
-Oh, yeah.
The driver may have been
William Summerfield,
177 Decatur Street,
Ludlow, Illinois.
-One of you stay on the scene.
The other investigate
the Ludlow address.
Ten-four.
Car 254, KLP-646.
-Man, he's good.
-Heard the man.
-Wow.
-Yep.
-Well, this is it, I guess.
I don't know what to say, Carl.
[Engine starts]
I'll never forget you.
No. J -- just go.
Please.
-Looks like a girl's sweater.
-The car was attacked
by a sweater! Oh!
-So why is Walter Winchell
in this scene?
-Hey, it's my size!
-Come in, car 88.
-Uh, excuse me.
That's for me. I'm the man.
♪ Call me angel of
the morning, angel ♪
♪ Just dump-a-dum-dum-dum
Yello?
-Car 88 to Urbana,
McKenzie here. Go ahead.
-Car 254 has failed to report.
Is that car in your area?
-I beg your pardon!
-No, not here.
-Ten-four, car 88.
This is KLP-646 Urbana
calling car 254.
Come in, car 254.
-Wait a minute. McKenzie!
McKenzie! You're breaking
every rule in the book!
-Urbana to car 254.
Come in, car 254.
-Uh, Houston,
we've got a problem.
-Urbana to car 254.
Come in, car 254.
-I was the first one here.
-Hello, I'm at Ludlow!
-It's really dark!
-The whole town's destroyed!
-It's really neat.
-Everybody is gone!
-I'm lonely.
-You got to do something!
You won't believe this!
Send help, lots of help, quick!
-Uh, oh, forget it.
-Executive producer
Steven Bochco.
-Yeah, basically
I run the army.
Yep. How are you guys
doing over there?
-I don't feel very fun today.
Come on. Just come on.
-The director's brother-in-law,
ladies and gentlemen!
[Clapping]
-What? Hey!
You know, Bert I.
did all this in one take.
-Amazing.
-You know, when I was a boy,
we didn't have fast movies.
Sometimes, we had to wait
three or four hours
for something to happen.
-I love that story.
Anyone needing to go
to the bathroom, go now!
-♪ How will you make it
on your own ♪
-She's got her radio tuned
to the marching band station.
-All Sousa, all the time!
-Must get Vivarin.
-[Imitating snoring]
-Now, this is an improv
that really went nowhere.
[Laughter]
-Okay, men, Private Reese
is feeling vulnerable today.
It's up to us to cheer him up.
-Your Hover Buick will getyou there in style, Hover Buick.
-[Gasps] Servicemen, great!
-[Imitating tires squealing,
crashing]
-All right, lady,
just follow the arrows.
-Any chance of getting through?
-Nope.
-What happened?
-Look, lady, just detour.
Will you, please?
-Don't make me pull you
from your car
and beat you with
my night stick.
-Hmm.
-Hmm, quiet, smooth ride.
-Turbo hydromatic.
Oh, now they're going
to have to turn
the rear projection
screen around, too.
-Guys, this is so not Illinois.
-[Laughter]
-Hm.
[Humming]
-Hmm, wonder what
they're doing here.
Well...
-Gee, martial law is fun.
♪ La da da
-Whoa, that
is a Texas-style camera.
-Tell them to take that detail
out of there.
The old man is
sending a replacement.
-That's my line.
Finally remembered.
-I'm sorry, soldier.
I should have explained.
I'm Audrey Aimes,
National Wire Service.
-Yes, ma'am.
-How do I get there?
-Sorry. My orders are to let
no one through.
-Well, that surely doesn't
include the press.
-I'm sorry, ma'am.
No one is what the old man said.-Good job today, Lance.
Carry on.
-Well, was it very bad?
-So ashamed.
-Many get hurt?
-Look, lady,
you're not going to fish
any information out of me.
Now, why don't you get back
on the main road?
It's about a mile south.
-Hear that, guys?
I really told her off.
"Mile south"! [Chuckles]
-He likes me.
I think we're dating.
-Oh, I locked my keys
in the car.
What the -- Oh.
[Humming]
[Engine starts]
-Hey, the car startedwithout her even doing anything.
-[Imitating dramatic music]
♪♪
-Jimmy Jam does his thing.
-Until further notice...
-I'm Paul Frees.
-...all traffic will continue
to be routed
around the Ludlow area
according to special orders...
-Good morning.
-I'm turning myself in.
-I'd like to see
your commanding officer.
-Here's a little
something for you.
-Well, I'm sorry,
but the colonel is busy.
-Too busy for these?
-Perhaps Captain Barton
can help you.
[Telephone rings]
-"I am deaf.
Please give me money."
Hmm.
-Send her in.
-Ma'am.
-File on Dalton Trumbo, sir.
-This is the report on the
situation you asked for, sir.
-Thanks, Lieutenant.
Sit down, please.
-Now get up again.
[Laughs]
-Are you the Audrey Aimes
who covered Korea
for that picture magazine?
-That's right.
-Well, I hated it!
-I read the book you wrote
after the war.
Liked it very much.
-Well, thank you.
-You're with
National Wire Service now.
-I was on my way
to Chanute Field
to do a picture story on a new
jet plane they're unveiling,
and I ran into a roadblock.
-So?
-Yeah, you're right.
What was I thinking?
-Captain, there was a town
beyond that roadblock,
a town that isn't there anymore.
-Until we find out
exactly what happened,
we'd like to avoid publicity.
-You have any idea
what happened?
-I'm sorry, Miss Aimes.
-Maybe after this whole
cover-up,
we can have coffee some time?
-Captain, you can't suppress
a story like this.
-We're not trying to,
Miss Aimes,
but until we have more facts...
-♪ This is the army,
Audrey Aimes ♪
-Will you give us your word
you won't release a story
until we give the go-ahead?
-You have my word.
-God, your hair
smells wonderful.
-Sometime during the night,
the town of Ludlow
was completely demolished.
-And?
-Town's population,
about 150 people, vanished.
-Vanished?
-No bodies, nothing.
-It was some
David Copperfield stunt.
-Well, there must be
some trace.
-I know it's hard to believe,
Miss Aimes.
-But I'm Koko Taylor!
-Special detail combed through
the wreckage for two solid hoursand couldn't find a thing.
-Two solid hours?
-Was it an explosion?
-We don't know.
-On account of the fact
we're not very smart.
-150 people just don't
vanish into thin air.
-We're still trying to
find out what happened.
If you'd like to sit in.
-Thank you. I would.
-I've got a clarinet in my car.
-Hey.
[Grunting]
-Dave, what time did you
leave Ludlow last night?
-Must have been after 11:00.
-Arnold Ziffel's father!
-My father-in-law was watching
the television news at 10:30,so I sat there and watched that.
-Then I caught "Letterman."
-And my daughter wanted me
to sit there and talk a while.
Then I got to thinking
that I had to get up early.
-Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Your point, please?
-So I took off.
-Did you notice
anything strange...
-[As Grandpa Munster] Hoiman!
-...about the house
or about the way
the family acted?
-Other than wanting my
son-in-law to diaper me, nope.
-No. Same as always.
-When you were driving
out of town...
-Nice likeness.
-...nothing out of the way
in the street, the building
or the sky,
no unusual lights,
some sound or...
-Objection, your -- Oh.
-Well, I heard something
that sounded like thunder.
-Couldn't see it so good
because of the rain.
-But it could be
a plane went over.
-You are so high.
-All right, Dave.
I can call on you again
if I need you?
-Oh, yes.
-You know you can call me, Tad.
-Edna?
-My next guest, Rosemary!
[Imitates cheering]
-Is that
the telephone company's
official transcripts?
-It was a mistake.
I -- I didn't mean it!
Oh.
-The last call to Ludlow
was at 11:59 p.m.
-When did you first notice
anything wrong
with the Ludlow connection?
-Andrew Jackson!
-Old Hickory!
-I phoned the company linesmen
to go out there right away.
-So the telephone lines
could have gone down
anywhere between 11:59 and 4:45.
-Yes, yes, is that
what you want?
-All right, thanks.
You've been very helpful.
-Man, she's a tough old bird.
-Okay, bye.
-Oh, Colonel Sturgeon,
Miss Aimes,
National Wire Service.
-How do you do?
-Audrey Aimes, I've read a lot
of your stuff,
seen a lot of your photographs.
-Reading your cleavage now.
Oh.
-Yello?
-Yes?
-Set to go, sir,
whenever you're ready.
-I'll be right there.
-I got to pick up Phil
at play practice.
-I hope you understand
our problem,
our need to keep this quiet.
-Yes.
Captain briefed me.
-Then he pantsed me.
-If anyone wants me,
I can be reached
in Ludlow by radio.
-Yes, sir.
-How's chances of me
going along?
-Not this trip. Maybe later.
-Baby later?
-Any case, not until we know
what's out there.
-Well, by the way, Colonel,
my camera was taken from me
at the road block
by one of your men.
-I'll give orders
to have it released.
-I'll take the long way
out of here.
A Bert I. Gordon film,
after all.
See you.
-What a loser!
-Oh, there has to be
a logical explanation for this.
A town of 150 people
just doesn't disappear.
-This one did.
-Yes, but in general,
they don'tdisappear.
That's my point.
♪♪
-Hey, now she's on "The Abbott
and Costello Show" set!
-Oh, man, I should have
taken home-ec or gone
into teaching or nursing,
like all of the other girls.
Gosh, I'm 21,
and I'm still not married.
Yello?
-Chicago mobile
service operator.
-I'd like to place
a person-to-person call,
please, to Mr. Norman Taggart.
-Me being one of the persons,
of course.
-National Wire Service.
The number is Murray Hill 44836.
-Man, I miss those
kind of phone numbers.
-In what city?
-New York.
-[As Frank Nelson]
Eeeeyeeessss?!
-You wind up that
jet plane story already?
-I'm not on the jet story.
Norm, listen.
I'm on to something
I think can be real big.
-Me!
-Mm-hmm.
-Oh, he's right-handed.
-Where?
Oh.
-Scribble, scribble, scribble,
scribble as though I'm writing.
-Huh?
What do you mean,
we can't print it?
-I've given my word to hold off
for a while.
Now listen, Norm.
-You're fired.
-A plane flew over Ludlow
last night about midnight,
just about the time
the lid blew off.
Check on it,
and check Washington.
See if they had an atomicinstallation in the Ludlow area.
-Okay.
-Who am I, your stringer?
-Call me back as soon as you
have anything, right?
Goodbye.
-Geez, her guy Friday.
-Cool.
[Engine starts]
-[Imitating exciting music]
-Ooh.
-Hey, we found 150 people!
You were right.
-Sorry, miss. You can't...
Oh, it's you again.
-I know I can't.
I'd like to have
my camera back, please.
Colonel Sturgeon said he was
going to speak to somebody.
-Hey, Corporal? Mathias?
She wants her camera back.
[Phone buzzes]
-I'll get it.
It's probably for me.
Yello?
-Hi. Do you know
[speaks indistinctly] today?
-What's the score?
-Wrong track, baby.
The airlines confirm
a commercial liner over Ludlow
at 12:03 last night.
And there are no atomic
installations,
secret or otherwise,
within 75 miles of Ludlow.
-Well, it was a possibility.
-The only people who've been
playing around with
radioactive materials
in your vicinity
is the U.S. Department
of Agriculture.
-Anything there?
-Department of Agriculture?
-Yeah!
-Yeah, they've got
an experimental project
just outside Paxton.
-U.S. Department of Agriculture,Illinois Experimental Station.
-Mm-hmm.
Okay, I've got that.
I -- I'll keep in touch.
-I got to go.
I've got someone in my office.
-I have a city idea -- Chicago.
I think it might work.
[Laughter]
-Let's get out of here.
-Yeah.
[Tom Servo whistling]
[Doors thud and creak]
-[Whistles]
-Wow, I don't know about
this movie, you guys.
I mean, nothing's happening.
-No.
-I think maybe we should
call the Mads.
We can do that, right?
-Well, I guess,
but I wouldn't advise it.
-Yeah, I mean, why get them
involved, huh?
-Well, I mean, I just think
we should call the Mads.
Why don't we call the Mads?
-I don't know.
-♪ My baby takes
the morning train ♪
♪ She works till 9:00
Frank?
I could not stop picking
at that pan of lemon bars.
I ate half the pan!
You're so lucky.
You could eat anything
and not worry.
-Oh, pa-shaw.
I'd give anything to have
that complexion of yours.
-Oh, Frank.
-Hey, wow.
Vicki is on!
-[Sighs]
Whew!
You know, Frank, this is exactlywhat I wanted to do today,
just have the whole day
to ourselves.
-I'm declaring this
National Our Day.
[Both chuckle]
Please, do not let me eat
all of this.
-Well, I shouldn't.
[Both chuckle]
Oh, my God, Frank.
Switch on a game.
Switch on a game!
[Stadium crowd cheering]
-Ay-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi.
Wow.
-So, uh, I guess we can call
the Mads, huh?
-Yeah. Yeah.
-But you know what?
-Yeah?
-I don't think I'm going to
do that for a while.
-Unh-unh.
-No.
-We'll be right back.
♪♪
-[Shudders]
-Wow.
-Strange fellers.
-Come on in.
Just working on plutonium.
-Herman Badillo!
-I'm looking for
the Fornstein wedding.
-Tomatoes like bronze.
-Wow, Suddenly Salad.
-Excuse me.
-Man, those are
cherry tomatoes.
-I beg your pardon.
-I never promised you
a rose garden.
-Hey! This is the produce
department, isn't it?
-I beg your pardon.
-We're working overtime
to keep Dom DeLuise fed.
-The more he ignores me,
the more I'm attracted to him.
-Oh!
-Hello.
-I'm Peter Graves.
-Oh, hello.
I -- I spoke to him,
but I guess he didn't hear me.
-Oh.
He's a deaf mute.
-You insensitive little...
-Working with radiation
can be dangerous.
-I smelled that!
-Accident last year cost him
his speech and his hearing.
-And 600 bucks.
-I'm sorry.
I'm looking for
the project director.
-I'm the project director.
My name is Ed Wainwright.
-I'm mute, too.
-What can I do for you?
Oh, excuse me a minute.
-Kind of a vague sign language,
isn't it?
-I'm sorry, Frank.
-Oh, he dropped
his chocolate sampler.
-Nothing to worry about,
just a slight catastrophe.
-Do you have these
catastrophes very often?
-Well, as often as we have
government cover-ups.
-All the time.
It's hard to keep these
little things from getting in.
These are snails.
Last summer,
it was caterpillars,
and after that, it was
grasshoppers by the drove.
-This guy eats anything.
-And just last week,
it was beetles.
-Now it's bagel dogs.
-What can I do for you?
-Well, Mr. Wainwright,
I'm Audrey Aimes.
I'm with
National Wire Service.
I suppose you've heard
about what happened in Ludlow.
-Yes.
-I'd like to kiss you full
on the mouth.
-I'm trying to find out
what was responsible,
and it occurred to me
that radiation of some sort
might have caused
the destruction out there.
-No, I don't think so.
Here.
-Let me show you a giant
crouton we're working on.
-We're the only people
around here
using radioactive materials.
-[Imitating humming]
-Maybe I shouldn't be keeping
my lunch in here.
I don't know.
-And isotopes aren't explosive.
-And they're packed
with vitamins!
-So I'm afraid your answer
isn't here.
-Oh, I see.
-The big brush off.
-Hmm.
-Tell me, is this thing
really a strawberry?
-Yes.
These are tomatoes.
-And those are turkey franks.
-This, we hope,
is the future
of the American farmer
and, for that matter,
all farmers everywhere.
-Can you eat them?
-No, not yet.
-I don't even like tomatoes.
-But we hope to develop one day
a hybrid that can be eaten.
-How is it there hasn't been
any publicity on this?
-Oh, there have been a few
stories in the farm journals,
but to most of the public,
these giants are just
freaks of nature
with no practical value.
-Ah, get this thing off me!
-But how do they get so big?
-Well, radiation causes
photosynthesis,
that is the growing process,
to continue night and day.
Radioisotopes act as
a sort of artificial sun.
-That's it.
Reel her in, boss.
-Sun that never sets.
-It's fascinating.
Now tell me, what's he doing?
-Well, that's plant food,
essential minerals.
-And he's eating it.
-Keeps the plants from
burning themselves out.
They have to be fed constantly.
Actually, the fruit
would grow much larger
if we didn't limit
the stimulation.
-Speaking of stimulation...
-Maybe you'd like to do
a story on us.
I'd be glad to tell you more
about the work.
-Ooh, schmooze overdrive.
-Thank you very much.
I'd be very interested.
Well, right now I'm working
on this Ludlow story.
-If you could see my hands
right now, you'd be horrified!
-Bye.
-Don't start.
-♪ That's my mother, dear
♪ She helps me
through everything I do ♪
-Three jerks and a Jill.
-Colonel!
-You here?
-Well, they wouldn't
let me inside, so...
-Oh, Colonel, Springfield
is on the line.
-Colonel, you just got back
from Ludlow.
You said after you got back,
I could go.
-I said maybe.
-Well, how about it?
-Tomorrow, it'll be
open to the press.
-Oh, Colonel, be fair!
I played ball with you.
Give me the jump on the other
reporters who'll be in here.
At least let me take
some pictures in Ludlow.
I promise I won't put them
on the wire till tomorrow.
-Well, I guess
you're right that,
for effort anyway.
Barton, take Miss Aimes
to Ludlow.
-Yes, sir!
-And I hope you have
a strong stomach.
-Gabe Kaplan's performing.
-Oh.
-He's nice.
-We're going to take
some pictures in Ludlow.
If we're not back in 15 minutes,better come in after us.
-Check out that guy over there.
He's taken a few in the head.
-Let them through!
-Oh, that wouldn't stop
a kid on a Big Wheel.
-Toughest job you'll
ever love, ugh.
-All right, Captain.
Way to go! Whoo!
-Huh?
Suddenly, it's turned
into "Topper."
-Somebody turn down
the Albert Glasser music.
I can't concentrate.
-I wish the Larsons would take
better care of their yard.
-Oh, it's a disgrace.
-Oh, look at that.
-My goodness!
-Well, want to stop and loot?
-Hey, it's a Star City.
-Oh, look, there's
a perfectly good 2x4.
-This was no boating accident!
-[Imitating dramatic music]
-I've had enough.
-I can't stand reality.
-Whoa, Colonel!
-Some people use calendars
to tell age.
I could use ruins to count mine.
-Oh, am I here, too?
-I was 25 when I went
through Seoul after the shells.
-I'm wearing panties right now.
-I was 20 when I took my camera
into Cologne and Berlin
after World War II.
-24 when I saw Dylan
at the Bitter End.
-Must be used to it by now.
-Captain, there's some things
you never get used to.
-Yeah, like underarm odor.
-Thanks.
How about my kiss?
-How about a drink to wipe away
some memories?
A good way to get rid
of those jitters.
I know a little place --
-How do 150 people vanish
into thin air?
-Yeah, terrible.
Martinis?
-Well, around this part
of the country,
things seem to have
a way of vanishing.
Only a couple of months ago,
it was a warehouse.
Kind of fell apart overnight,
just like Ludlow.
-Goodbye, Captain.
-Oh, hello?
-Okay. Okay.
You can have your raise.
-Hey.
He saw and hears something.
[Car door closes]
-Women on the verge
of an atomic breakdown.
-She wants me so bad.
-Let's get on with
the harassment
so we can get some work done.
-Hello, Frank.
-Hi.
Did you decide to come back
and do a story on us?
-Well, no.
As a matter of fact,
I came back for some help.
I'd like you to do me a favor.
-Oh, yes.
-Anything I can.
-Does it involve
taking my pants off?
-Remember the warehouse
that was destroyed
about three months ago?
-Uh-huh.
-I want you to take me
to see it.
-Then to dinner and a movie.
-Oh, well, I, uh --
I'd like to,
but I've got too much work
on my hands right now.
How about tomorrow?
-Three months ago,
a warehouse was destroyed,
and the one person
in it vanished.
This morning,
Ludlow was destroyed.
All the people in it vanished.
-Coincidence?
Read the book.
-Don't you think there's
a possible tie-up?
-Look, lay off.
Lay off!
-It's possible, I suppose.
What do you want me to do?
-Just ride out there with me
and take a look at it.
-I don't understand
what good that'll do.
The authorities
investigated it thoroughly.
-Look, I'm coming on to you.
Don't you get it?
-The sheriff thinks in terms
of crime and publicity.
You're a scientist.
You think in terms
of cause and effect.
Maybe you will see something
that the sheriff missed.
-[Chuckles] Oh, that shouldn't
be too difficult.
Still, I-I don't know.
-Frank, that's filthy!
I should wash your hands
out with soap.
-What's he saying?
-[Laughs] He says that, uh,
that your lips are easy to read,
that your theory makes you
a very bright girl in his book,
and that he'd like
to go along with us.
-And he's being held here
against his will.
Oops.
-Peter, no!
-No, stop!
-I didn't want to see it.
Whew.
-When you barge into people's
lives and drag them off
to places they don't
really want to go,
aren't you sort of in danger
of becoming unpopular?
-Slug Bug!
-Ow.
-Oh, I thought...
-How'd you pick
such an occupation?
-Wait, this isn't
a stick shift!
Aaah!
-I guess I was just born
inquisitive.
Ever since I can remember,
I wanted to know the why
and where for just
about everything I saw.
I inherited my knack
for the camera from Dad.
-Yourdad, as a matter of fact.
-My curiosity supplied
the nose for news,
and the camera
supplied the memory.
-[Chuckles]
-So there you have it.
-Whatever.
-What about you?
Have you always been
interested in science?
-Well, after my German dance
hall days...
-Oh, I guess I always have been
in one way or another.
I used to fool
around with radios
and anything electrical
when I was a kid.
I was a radar officer
during the war,
and then I went into this
when I got out.
-Look, let's just play
the radio for a while, hm?
-Oh, yes, I remember now
that every time
I read one of your articles,
it was datelined from some area
of flood or famine or war.
Made me realize
what a sheltered life
we scientists really lead.
-What do you think of that?
-Sheltered?
Look what happened to Frank.
-Yeah, watch this.
[Screaming] Hey, Frank!!
[Laughs]
♪♪
-Geez, Frank, you should have
thought of that before we left.
-Doesn't look that great,
but they've got great
onion rings here.
-Mm.
-Oh, yeah.
-Huh?
-What?
-What the...
-Hey, this is even worse
than that other stuffthat we didn't know what it was.
-Well, it's a fixer-upper.
That's for sure.
-Looks to me as though
some force had to push
these walls out from the inside?
-Der, hey.
-Think it was an explosion?
-No, it couldn't have been.
Any explosion big enough
to destroy this warehouse
would certainly
have been heard in Ludlow.
-Well, at least
we saved this hat.
-Wonder what they
kept stored here.
-Wheat, almost
a million bushels.
-Wow.
-That's a lot of wheat.
-It was surplus to keep themarket from being over-supplied.
-I hate wheat.
-Does it strike you
as a little strange
that out of all that wheat,
there's not a grain
left anywhere?
-No, that's
nature's way, Audrey.
Birds probably cleaned up
the leavings.
-[As Woody Allen]
Geez, I'm deaf.
They're talking
about wheat over here.
-That's Frank's way of yelling.
-Wha -- wha -- what?
-Wow, that's
a whole lot of skirt.
-I see what you mean, Frank.
-What is it, Ed?
-What -- what did he say?
-You see how barren
this ground is?
-Wow.
-I don't know. I've seen
horses leave it like this.
-Oh, this is deeper than horses
go and much more thorough.
-And much more fun.
-Practically down
to the roots.
The horses pick and choose.
They leave patches.
-I was in "Fury,"
so I know that.
-This is completely barren.
-Please don't say that word.
I'm very sensitive right now.
-Well, leave it to old Frank.
He'll make a botanist
out of me yet.
-You were head
of a government lab,
and you need lessons in botany?
-Well, just lay off!
-I try to teach him what I can
about my field of study.
He tries to teach me
what he can about his.
-Aren't you a botanist?
-No, no.
I'm an entomologist,
the study of insects.
-Oh, fascinating.
-Then how come you're working
with plants?
-Golly, you're right!
-Well, the existence
and development of plants
and insects are
very closely related.
They're highly dependent
on one another.
As a plain matter of fact, onecouldn't live without the other.
-Mm-hmm.
-Bogus!
-That's why
I can't understand.
Ground like this is usually
teeming with insects.
-Yeah.
-This area is
completely devoid of it.
-Hm.
-Do you like Fiddle Faddle?
-I think I'd like to get
some shots of this.
I'm going back to the car
for my camera.
-I'd really like to see you rub
your forearms together.
-Whoa.
-Hey, an Indian Head penny!
-Oh, yeah.
-Here, let me help you.
-[Groans] Oh.
[Chirping]
-What was that?
-I don't know.
-Oh, it might be coming from
behind that
rather large grasshopper.
-I think...
-Oh, luckily the grasshopper
is closed captioned.
-Frank, would you quit clowning
with that giant grasshopper?
-Oh, no! Stop!
-He's signing, "Ah!"
-Oh, no.
-You can't save him.
-Get in the car.
-Quickly, get a really
big applesauce jar
with holes poked in the lid!
-Hey, Diane Arbus,
why don't you take a picture?
You've got a camera.
-We'll send help!
Bye-bye!
-So, feel like Chinese?
-The Geiger counter
showed no radioactivity
to speak of, sir.
Only background.
-There's got to be
an explanation somewhere.
-I've got your explanation
for you, Tom.
-We've got bugs.
-Now, listen.
You've known me ever
since I came to Paxton.
You know I'm not
given to hysteria,
and you've got to listen to me
with an open mind.
-[Shouting gibberish]
-What are you talking about?
-I'm talking about
giant locusts.
-Wow.
-Giant locusts are responsible
for all of this.
-I love it.
-No evidence of any explosion,
Colonel.
The buildings look more like
they were hit
with a battering ram.
We found these guns
at the scene,
the kind people
keep in their home.
They've been fired.
-Can I go home now?
-Lieutenant.
-Now, listen, Tom.
These are 8-feet tall,
some even bigger.
They're vicious,
merciless killers.
-Now, Ed.
-Stops him cold with that,
"Now, Ed," every time.
-Lieutenant!
Phone Springfield again.
Tell them I'm still waiting
for those specialists.
-Yes, sir.
-Frank Johnson is dead.
He was killed not
half an hour ago.
-It was horrible.
-Obviously you are both
under strain --
-Won't you listen?
You've got to get some soldiers
out there
before more people are killed.
-Miss Aimes,
the governor asked me
to exercise discretion
in dealing with you.
Please don't make it any harder
for me than it is.
-You have to believe us.
Listen, you've seenthe giant plants out at the lab.
-Are you trying to tell me
you bred these things?
-Yep, then I deep-fry them.
-In a sense I did, yes.
-Hey, hey, it's Ike!
Say hi to Ike, everyone.
-Hi, Ike!
-I like Ike.
-They ate some of the
radioactive plant food.
Well, their cell division
accelerated immediately.
That is, they started
to grow abnormally fast.
-So it's your fault!
-They have to have a constant
food supply
to sustain this growth.
So a couple of months ago,
they wandered into the grain
elevator outside of town.
When they grew to this giantsize, they pushed their way out.
-Well, they just pushed
the building down?
-Yes!
-Okay, okay, forget locusts.
Giant panda bears, and they fly!
-One of them has
the strength of 10 men.
There are probably
200 or 300 of them.
-So last night, not satisfied
with eating the grain,
they came to Ludlow?
-Yes.
-[Chuckles]
Even if I went for your story
about the size,
it would be hard to believe
they would attack people.
Sergeant?
-Have these people killed.
-That report come in
from the chemists?
-No, not yet, sir.
-Why won't you listen?
-I am listening!
-We saw Frank Johnson killed
by a giant locust.
-Sure, and there are reliable
people who've also seen
flying saucers
and weird little men from Mars.
-Well, take another look
at that town out there,
or have you found the answer?
-God, I want pork right now.
-Lieutenant?
-Yes, sir?
-I'm taking a detail
out for a look around.
You're to keep radio contact.
I want 10 men.
Get them on the truck.
-Yes, sir.
-All right, Ed.
-Strap this on.
-You can show me the exact spot
where you saw...
well, whatever it was you saw.
-No.
-Well, after all,
it's his grasshopper.
-His ribbings are so much
less gentle of late.
-It's a good thing they're not
huge eyebrow mites!
-Why, the Joads are armed
at the teeth.
California.
-♪ We're not afraid
of big old bugs! ♪
-♪ Army guys like gentle hugs
-Well, some.
-That too windy back there
for you guys?
-[Imitates squeaking]
-What, is the truck just going
to dump them?
-Is this a snipe hunt?
[Imitating beeping]
-All right.
-All right, men.
-Let's get the enemy.
Let's kill 'em all.
[Indistinct chatter]
-Defending countries.
Wow, rhubarb.
-Men, we're going to dig us
some crazy grasshoppers.
-Why didn't they give us nets
instead of rifles?
-Mm-hmm.
-[Chuckles]
Observational humor.
-All right, men. Fan out.
-That's one of my
favorite mountains
in Illinois back there.
-Hey, somebody is throwing out
nice roofing material here!
-Here's the spot, Tom.
-He wet them here.
-Where's the body?
-There isn't any body,
just like Ludlow.
-I don't think I've implied
there would be a body!
-There isn't any body.
-All right, men,
into the woods.
♪♪
-I don't know, Crow.
It's probably just me...
-Yeah.
-...but the whole idea
of a screenplay based around
the life of Peter Graves...
-Yeah.
-...it just spells
box office poison.
And then to go and narrow
the focus so much.
-Here, let me sizzle it
for you, Mike.
Peter Graves went to the
University of Minnesota, right?
-I guess. I don't know.
-I guess nothing!
The man went to the U of M,
and that's exactly
what my screenplay exploits.
-Well, can we just get on
with this, please?
-Yes.
[Clears throat] Here we go.
"Just Plain Peter:
The U of M Years"
or "Peter Graves Goes to Collegeat the University of Minnesota,"
a screenplay by Crow T. Robot.
-Okay, okay.
Let's go.
-I'm only doing this becauseI need the stage time, pin beak.
-Okay, Servo.
-Okay, okay.
Act one, Peter Graves enrolls
at the University of Minnesota.
-Okay, okay.
Here we go.
Hi!
I'm the registrar.
May I help you?
-[As Peter Graves] Yes.
I'm Peter Graves,
and I'd like to enroll
at the University of Minnesota.
-That's...
-Oh, uh, act two.
Mike, you've got to help me
with the cards
because I don't have them.
-Oh, right. Okay.
Thank you.
Act two, Peter Graves
attends his first class.
-Hi, I'm Peter Graves.
Is this Biology 101?
-Yes.
-Good. I'm Peter Graves,
and I'm in the right class.
-Huh.
Um, act three.
Thank you, Mike.
Act three, uh, Peter Graves
enjoys dorm life.
-Okay, hold on here.
Think fast!
-A-ha! I'm Peter Graves,
and I'm enjoying
some good-natured ribbing
with one of my many new pals
here at the University
of Minnesota.
-Act four,
extracurricular activities.
-[Normal voice] Oh, this is
great, this one. He says...
-Just...
-Oh.
[As Peter Graves]
I'm Peter Graves,
and I was wondering if you coulddirect me to the natatorium,
as I'm attending a swim meet.
-It's that way.
-Thank you.
I'm Peter Graves.
-Okay. Uh, act five,
Peter finds his calling.
-I'm Peter Graves,
and I'm beginning to take
an interest in the theater arts
and speech communications
here at the University
of Minnesota.
-Crow, how many --
how many acts are there?
-[Normal voice] Uh, 15.
-[Laughs] Okay.
Look, Crow,
I'm not criticizing here,
but were you worried
about the redundancy factor
or not, or...?
-Well, I felt my point was
important enough to risk that,
but let's do the climax.
I think you'll really like it.
-Oh, yeah.
-Just skip to the climax.
-Flip all the cards over now.
-There we go.
-Good.
Act 15, graduation.
-[As Peter Graves]
I'm Peter Graves.
Thank you for the opportunity
of learning
at this fine institution.
As I look back, I remember
fondly my enrollment process
where, had you been there,
you might have heard me say,
"Hi, I'm Peter Graves,
and I'd like to enrollat the University of Minnesota."
Or the time when I,
Peter Graves --
-That's it!
Crow, you are way out there!
-[Normal voice] What? Hey!
-W-w-w-w-w-way out!
-I got to agree
with him, Crow.
Not much...Nope.
-Mike, no matter what you
or Servo may think
of my little screenplay,
if it's convinced
just one person out there
that Peter Graves went
to the University of Minnesota,
then I've done my job.
[Alarm buzzing]
[As Peter Graves]
I'm Peter Graves,
and we've got movie sign on A&E.
Oh, look out, Barney,
Ferris, help me! Aah!
[Doors thud and creak]
-Oh, movies. Oh, hi.
-That's enough.
-All right.
-[Imitating dramatic music]
-[Whistling]
♪♪
-Hey, Frank.
-How was the brothel
last night?
-Maybe we can train
one of these giant
what's its to pull a plow, huh?
-Everything is not a joke, Ted.
-Huh?
-I don't like this place.
-Oh, take it easy.
-You know, maybe
they were big ants.
Didn't see them real good,
did you?
-You know, grasshoppers
are good eating.
-Yeah?
Mustard or ketchup?
-Shouldn't they all be
different ethnic types?
-No, no kidding.
I ate them once down Mexico.
-Well, you better
watch your step.
They're liable to get even.
-We're having a light-hearted
conversation
in the midst
of unbearable tension.
-Well, at least it's a nice day
to be out, eh?
-They must have seen something.
Mr. Wainwright's a scientist.
He's trained
to see things right.
-Well, these days, they blame
the atoms for everything.
Bad health, bad crops,
bad weather.
-Bad lieutenant.
-Now it's grasshoppers.
-They couldn't have just
dreamed up this guy
Frank being knocked off.
-Ah.
-Now, were your glasses
in a case,
or did they just drop
out of your pocket?
-[As Arnold Horshack]
Oh, oh, Mr. Kot-tare!
[Chirping]
-What would Mitchell
do right now, huh?
-[As Abner Kravitz] Gladys,
quit bugging the Stephens.
[Chirping continues]
-There's Bernard Herrmann
music out there!
-They sense I'm Peter Graves.
[Chirping continues]
-They're all too embarrassed
to admit they hear anything
-Hey, uh, is this
what we're looking for?
-Wow.
-Yow.
-Sit, stay!
-Just get a giant screen door!
-Hey, let's pull one leg off
and watch it try to walk!
Oh!
-I think we should have waitedfor the sanctions
to take effect!
-Uh, you see, if you're going
to have a war,
you should rake first.
-Oh, yeah.
[Gunfire]
-[Imitating gunfire]
-Just run in that
general direction.
[Gunfire]
-We're going to get
a lot of Raid, right?
We're going to go get
a whole lot of Raid, right?
-Exterminate with
extreme prejudice.
-Oh, this is a bug hunt, man.
-♪ When you wish upon a star
[Laughs]
-You know, sometimes you can't
hear the pincer with
your name on it.
-Hey, you guys know
where we can get some
decent wheat around here?
-I better get the place ready.
Yeah.
-America responds to the new
Robert Urich,
Faye Dunaway sitcom.
-Al Bundy takes command!
-Can I, uh, get a ride
with you guys?
-Just help yourself
to a gun, Peter.
[Indistinct shouting]
Come on.
-♪ John Jacob
Jingleheimer Schmidt ♪
-Oh, my God.
-Insects trained by
Rudd Weatherwax.
-One weekend a month, my ass!
-Well, that went well.
-And every available man...
-I'm throwing a party!
-Also get some air support.
We'll bomb them out
of that forest.
-Yeah, that ought to hold
a little...
-What are you going to do?
-Going in there and wipe out
every last one.
-They'll slaughter you.
-Not this time.
-Dig this.
-I want light artillery
brought up with company H.
-You don't have enough men.
-There will be three regiments
out there tomorrow by 0300.
-You don't understand.You still don't have enough men.
-Not enough men for a couple
of hundred locusts?
-There are more than
a couple hundred.
-But you said before --
-That was before
I heard them screech.
The noise they made
convinces me there are more.
-How many are there?
-I don't know.
There could be
countless numbers.
I think you better call
in the regular army, Tom.
-Why would I get off calling
for the regular army
to handle some
oversized grasshoppers?
-Boys, boys, don't fight!
-Why, they'd section 8 me
right out of the service.
[Telephone rings]
-Lieutenant, take charge
of the east sector.
-Aah! What?
-You're making a mistake, Tom.
-Hi. Anyone for Nutter Butters?
-Excuse me, bum leg.
-I'm afraid he doesn't
understand how serious this is.
-Well, after all, he knows what
that military is capable of.
-Oh, just jump on me, too!
-That's just it.
He has faith
in regimental firepower
because he's seen it work.
-♪ Faith, faith, faith, baby
-They've never seen anything
like this before.
-Well, you've done all you can.
-No, no, I haven't.
In a way, I feel responsible,
Audrey.
-In a way?
-Everybody's in deadly danger
if those locusts break
out of the forest.
-Well, back to the salt mine.
-What are you going to do?
-I'm going to Washington.
Maybe the army people
will listen to me.
-I'll go with you.
Maybe I can help.
I saw them, too.
-All right.
-Mind if a catch a ride?
-We've got to convince
them, Audrey.
We may be witnessing
the beginning of an era
that will mean the complete
annihilation of man.
-Annihilation?
-What will I wear?
-Annihilation,
the beginning of the end.
-Well, real good then.
Bye-bye.
-And guests at
the beginning of the end stay
at the beautiful Capitol dome.
-Inferior guests stay at
the Defense Department Annex.
-This, gentlemen, is the enemy.
-Moving pictures.
-This locust, more commonly
known as the grasshopper,
is almost identical
to the giant locusts of Ludlow,
except for its size
and the fact
that the giants' wings
failed to develop.
They cannot fly.
-Now I'll get comfortable.
-The locust is intelligent,
and it's strong.
-He's armed.
-The locusts follow a leader.
-His name is Larry.
-Like the bee and the ant,
they're able to communicate
with each other.
-Ant bee?
-This communication, or call,
is produced by the hind legs.
-Let me demonstrate.
-This is the 1956 Australian
locust plague.
-And this is
the 1910 Fruitgum Company.
-An area of 400 square miles.
-Seen it!
-We've been plagued by locusts
since Biblical times.
-You're not funny!
-We have various forms
of combating them.
-Sit down!
-As a matter of fact,
in our own country,
the early settlers of
the Massachusetts Bay Colony...
-Ow! Ow!
-...armed themselves
with bundles of brush
and drove millions
of locusts into the sea.
-Neat.
-Now, today, despite the fact
that we've developed
powerful insecticides...
-I haven't got a series.
-...the locust still inflicts
damages to the tune of
$25 million
in the United States alone.
-Wow.
-California, Colorado, Texas.
-Uh, Connecticut.
-Even this small locust
will attack a man.
-Little bastard!
-It has two powerful jaws
and edged with sharp teeth.
-And their vicious gases.
-And they'll kill other insects
and devour them.
If no other insects
are available,
it becomes a cannibal...
-Hm.
-...turning on its own kind.
-She wants me.
-What in the good God
are you talking about?
-Now, you've seen
what the locust can do
in its normal size,
smaller than your thumb.
Imagine, if you will, a locust
that's grown bigger than a man
and is continuing to grow,
some larger than others,
but each one a deadly killer.
-I think it will go
something like this.
-I hope you realize
we haven't much time.
-You are a scientist,
Mr. Wainwright.
You know what locusts can do.
I'm a solider.
I know what guns can do.
-Together we could...
-I feel secure
the Illinois National Guard
can handle this situation.
-Just like they handled
the Chicago Convention.
-Did you want to say something,
General Hanson?
-No, sir.
-I'm deeply ashamed.
-I was greatly impressed with
your presentation, Wainwright.
I'm sure all of us were.
Thank you very much for coming.
-Go in peace, and send no more.
-I'm afraid my presentation
didn't impress you
quite enough, General.
-I don't understand you.
-I mean that when the locusts
start to move out
of that forest,
I'm not sure you'll be able
to stop them.
-What are you suggesting
we do, Mr. Wainwright?
-Hit them with everything
you've got now.
You need more men,
a lot more men.
You need tanks
and heavy artillery.
-As of now, the full strength
of the Illinois National Guard
is in the lines surrounding
the Ludlow, Illinois, forest.
-Go away now.
-As I said before,
Mr. Wainwright,
you are a scientist.
Why not leave the fighting
to the military?
-Did you just call me a wussy?
-Well, I guess I'll just leave
you a few of my brochures.
-No, that's fine.
Thank you.
[Phone buzzes]
-Urgent call from
Paxton, Illinois, sir.
-Here, you talk
in this end, sir.
-General Short, here.
-General Shorthair?
-Oh, I don't know, stuffing!
Whatever you make.
-[Muffled] You've got
to help us, General.
-I see.
-We've got apple juice up
to our kneecaps.
Oh, please!
You've got to send them quick.
-Matt, you will fly to Paxton
with Mr. Wainwright.
You will take
charge of operations.
-Hey, I'm vindicated!
How many dead?
-Mr. Wainwright,
I owe you an apology.
The locusts have broken
through our defense lines,
thousands of casualties.
Our troops are reorganizing
to prevent Paxton itself
from being overrun.
-I am trying not to laugh, sir.
-[Imitating "Indiana Jones"
theme]
-The hill position in the
suburbs of Paxton must be held.
Otherwise, the 100 miles betweenPaxton and Chicago lie open.
-Can I get some nuts?
-General, we can't land
in Paxton, sir.
-Why not?
-It just came
over the radio, sir.
Giant locusts have
overrun Paxton at 1400.
-[Muffled] I told you so.
-Head for Chicago.
-Yes, sir.
-Well, no more lunches
at Milda's Cafe, huh?
♪♪
-"Dear Abby, I'm an elderly
woman who doesn't enjoy s--"
Oh, this came
to the wrong place!
-Captain, I want
these positions held.
I want them held at all costs,
if humanly possible.
Captain, have your map people
immediately turn out
300 overlays showing the Chicagodefense line as tentatively set.
Yes?
-Thank you,
Sergeant Whisper Thin.
-Yes, nothing gets tobacco
juice out of your clothes.
-Boy, I read slow.
-Major Everett.
-Our road trip to Peoria
is canceled.
-What about squadron 12?
-They haven't reported
in yet, General.
-Well, let me know
the moment you hear.
-Yes, sir.
-I'll be with you in a moment.
-Okay, son.
-Hill, you will proceed at once
to temporary GHQ central sector
and assume command.
-Robert Frost!
-You will order
the 81st armored division
to proceed without delay
from Fort Sheridan to Chicago.
Have the CTU report to me
upon arrival.
-And get this man an arm.
-Request the Defense Department
to alert the following
divisions -- the First Armory,
the 40th, the First Airborne,
the 92nd, and the 76th.
-Okay, any salad with that?
-Now, what's your problem?
-At the rate refugees are
pouring into Chicago, General,
our emergency stocks
won't last long.
-Then we'll feed them
crickets, yeah.
-That's it.
-Ugh.
Now why did I do that?
-Toxaphene is one
we haven't tried.
How good is it?
-Almost as powerful
as chlordane.
-With no after taste.
-All right, ship 2,000 gallons
out to the base.
-Take a pint for yourself.
[Telephone rings]-Excuse me.
Hello?
-Bug lab.
-Speaking.
-Squadron 12 just reported.
They say they came down
in the day
and practically drowned
the enemy in insecticide.
-I just got a haircut,
and it hurts.
-The chlordane didn't even
slow them down.
-They threw it back
at me and laughed.
-You'll have to come up
with something stronger.
-I'll do my best, General.
Goodbye.
-How about chlordane
with a tiny drop of Retsin?
-That stuff is no good.
Forget it.
-It doesn't cause
enough birth defects.
[Dramatic music plays]
-Wow.
-Ah, what else can I do
around here to
make myself useful?
Ah, here we go.
-Oh, no, new petition
against tax again?!
-Dear God.
-Looks pretty bad, doesn't it?
-No, you look fine.
-I thought you went back
to New York.
-Well, the big story is here.
-Look, your editor
called you back
because it was too dangerous.
-I wanted to be here.
-Damn. God, yes.
-Nothing we've done so far...
-This boil.
-Insecticides, fire bombs,
nothing has done any good.
And so little time.
-Well, you're doing
everything you can.
-Well, everybody is,
but it's not good enough.
-Maybe if I tried to toss
a quarter into that tank.
-A time will come when the
beasts will inherit the Earth.
-There's your answer,
a fine pilsner!
-Lee Marvin in"The Bridges of Madison County."
♪♪
-Hey, General,
where are you going?
-[As George Patton]
I'm going to Decatur.
Gonna shoot that
paper-hanging son of a bitch!
-Aaah!
-Sorry about that. Sorry.
-Boy, just wait till
the grasshoppers show up, huh?
[Chuckles]
-All quiet in
the western suburbs.
♪♪
-No, there's no sign
of the locusts yet, General.
Out.
-Should we just continue
firing at random?
-The Jack Benny Program!
[Imitates crowd cheering]
-And with a lark of
five divisions to the west
and south --
-Mr. Mitchell!
-General Hanson is confident
that he can keep
the menace at bay.
-That's "Dennis the Menace."
-Units of the Air Forces
and Marines
are moving into position
to back up those forces
already deployed by the Army.
The one advantage our forces
hold over the enemy...
-Don't sit so close, dear.
-...is that they always reveal
their intention to attack.
-Which is nice.
-Before every attack,
the locusts send forth
this warning
in the form of
a high-pitched screech.
-They've got, like,
the Sun King's bell
on top of their TV.
-The screech increases
in intensity until it reaches
ear-shattering proportions.
-Sounds like Mariah Carey.
-When the screech reaches
its full intensity...
-Then I wet 'em.
-...the locusts attack.
-Copy!
-We've got every available man
on the line, Major,
and I think there's
no question of what will be.
-Hush, now.
[Chirping in distance]
-Oh, I love a spring rain.
-I shouldn't have worn
my butt dress.
-Oh, great. They're early.
[Shouting]
-The Cubs don't win the pennant!The Cubs don't win the pennant!
-Meanwhile, at the Boy Scout
jamboree at Pottawatomie Park.
-I want to drive your tank.
-I call the front.
-Wow, so far, it seems pretty --Oh, my God! Look out!
-Hold your fire, men.
-We'll negotiate!
-Cricket lighter. Just $1.49.
[Gunfire]
-Wow.
-Oh, I'm hit.
-They got Jiminy! Get 'em!
-We were pinned down near Elgin.
-Aurora was pretty bad.
-Whew!
God, it stunk in there! Whew!
-Sweat lodge.
-Okay, okay. Okay, got ya!
[Chuckles]
-Whoops. Oh, I'm sorry.
Let me clear the shot.
-This is where you step back
and say,
"Thank God for my exoskeleton."
-Now, this is flying officer
Jim Cavanaugh.
The Dan Ryan is covered
with tobacco juice.
You may want to try
an alternative route.
-Let's all welcome
Bob Hope, ladies and gentlemen!
-Even our best footage
can't stop them!
-Have you seen my mommy
and daddy?
Ah! [Sobs]
-Damn Nazi grasshoppers.
-Hi, I'm going to sneak
in here to say
hope you're enjoying the show.
Bye for now.
-Oh, I've got a great gun.
No, I don't need a bazooka.
-The Orkin Army will storm
the beaches of Lake Forest.
[Gunfire]
-We're going to have
to get organized.
We should not be losing
to grasshoppers, people!
[Gunfire]
-So is this protecting Chicago
at all costs, sir?
-They keep coming, General.
-They're lobbing aphids at us.
-...gathering in
a spearhead formation.
They're hammering at
a single point in our line.
-I don't know how,
but they've arranged air cover
from the Mexican Army.
-They cut off our supply lines
and ate the radio men.
-No grasshoppers were hurtin the making of this film, huh?
-I don't believe it. They're
using Hannibal's surprise!
-Wow.
-They keep coming, General.
Inch by inch,
they're moving closer.
Still they come,
wave after wave.
-They've broken our code,
and the sergeant was
a grasshopper undercover.
-They're coming.
-They're pouring through
a breach in our line.
They're all around us!
We're being cut off!
-Oh!
♪♪
-We interrupt this program
for an important announcement.
-Aaah!
-The giant locusts have reached
the Chicago South Side
and nearby suburbs.
I repeat.
The giant locusts have
reached the Chicago South Side
and nearby suburbs.
-They control
the cement business.
-Keep calm.
Take shelter in basements.
-Do not dress like grain.
-Do not panic.
-Attention please.
Attention please.
Keep moving.
Do not block the highway.
-Do not covet
they neighbor's manservant.
-...road at once.
-Stamp all fires dead out.
-Keep all traffic moving.
Do not panic.
-Oh, my God. Oh, geez.I remember the last time this...
Oh, yah.
-Hey, hey, I want to
a Chicago-style hot dog.
[Munching]
-In Grant Park,
on Lake Shore Drive.
-♪ Bum, bum
be-de-de-la-dum-dum ♪
[Imitating trumpet playing]
-Uh, excuse me. Am I on 24?
-Yes. Yeah. Come on, baby.
Comb that hair.
Oh, I wish I was a tub
of Dippity-Do.
Yes, yes.
Yeah. Oops.
-This is a single room!
-Ah, you women take so long
to get ready.
I'm kidding.
[Radio whirring]
-I didn't say
the skirt was ugly.
I said...
-General.
-Ed, Ms. Aimes,
grab a chair and sit down.
-They've got a picture
of Russ Bender, hmm.
-I sent for you
because of a new development
that may be favorable to us.
-Bruce Geller called.
-The locusts have stopped
their advance.
They're huddled in the alleys
and buildings
just outside the Loop.
-The locusts got cold.
When the temperature drops
below 68 degrees,
they just stop moving.
-Well, maybe now is the time we
could move in and destroy them.
-Well, they aren't
in hibernation, sir.
They'll move
if they're provoked,
and they're just
as deadly as ever.
-Just shoot me down.
-When the sun
comes out tomorrow,
they'll be active again.
-The Air Force is standing by,
a B-52 loaded with an atom bomb.
-Oh, good.
Maybe they'll get larger.
-You can't throw up
an atom bomb on Chicago.
-Sure, you can.
-Washington has given me
the authority to do
just that
as a last contingency.
If the bomb is dropped
early tomorrow,
there'll be no loss of life.
The city will be
evacuated by then.
-Well, what about the property?
There will be a billion dollars
worth of damage
and a site that's
too contaminated to rebuild on.
-I realize that.
-I just don't care.
-But if we don't drop the bomb,
Chicago will
almost certainly fall.
-Look, we'll move the Loop
to Schaumburg.
-The bomber crew is alerted.
We'll drop at dawn.
If we don't come up
with something by then,
I'll make a final check
with "Worsh-ington"...
-Washington.
-...and relay their okay.
-No Chicago?
Well, why not?
-Isn't there a chance
the locusts could die
in the night from the cold?
-No, not at this time of year.
-Anyway, they got blankets.
-It takes 24 hours of exposure
at 14 degrees.
-Is that cold or tame weather?
-Is there some way you could
drive them into the lake?
In Washington,
you said the settlers did that.
-Settlers?
-Hmm?
-Oh, yeah, people who settle.
-Oh, the early settlers
in Massachusetts did, literally,drive them into the sea,
but they weren't
dealing with giants.
[High-pitched whistling]
-Oh, that's my Darjeeling.
-Just a second.
-Wait a minute.
We can't drive them.
-We can invite them to leave.
-Not drive.
We could attract them, attract.
-I'll dress like
a sexy grasshopper!
-If we can reproduce their call,General, it might work.
It just might work.
-A call for insects?
-Call for insects!
Call for insects!
-Have you ever been
duck hunting, General?
-A duck call?
-Yes. There's one for bees, too.They use it in apiaries.
-A bee call?
-It might work.
-What do you need?
-A tennis ball,
an accordion,
and a picture of Don Ameche.
-I need, uh, I need
an audio oscillator.
I need an audio -- two,
two audio amplifiers...
-Th -- three, three,
three, four.
Make it four.
-I need an oscilloscope.
I need some high-frequency
radio equipment
and a boat, a fast boat.
-Hmm.
-Whatever you need, we'll get.
-Oh, then a bottle
of Johnnie Walker Blue.
-There's something
I have to get myself,
something that'll tell me
when I've succeeded.
-Well, what's that?
-A live giant grasshopper.
-Get out.
-I'm not with him.
-Here, live giant grasshopper.
Here, live giant
grasshopper, boy.
-All right, drop your
segmented thorax, and come out.
We've got your
blade of grass surrounded!
-♪ Sing whenever I sing
whenever I sing ♪
-Sir, please.
-Savages. Worse than
British soccer fans.
-Well, they got to be
around here somewhere.
[Engine revs]
-Hey, hey, hey.
They're stealing the truck!
-Hey!
-So long, suckers.
[Imitating chirping]
-Oh.
-All right, men.
Off the truck.
-Ow, ow.
-Major, I'd suggest that you
send some of them that way
and some down there
and you and I try the alley.
-Brilliant!
-Okay.
Now, you four men go that way.
You men, that way.
-Just go out, just anywhere.
You -- you know what you do.
-Go.
-What is this, a welcome
respite from all the action?
-You know, Major, lately,
I've been watching
the unfolding of me.
And yet, I can't love.
-I appreciate that,
yet I don't think
it's appropriate right now.
-Hmm.
-So, Doc, uh, how's the science
game working out for you?
I thought about
getting into science.
I got a "C"
in it in junior high.
Actually, it was interior designthat always thrilled me.
That was my knack for a while,
textures and...
-Hey, they just set off
the grasshopper alarm.
-♪ The night Chicago died
♪ Da, na, na na, na, na,
na, na, na ♪
-Shut up.
[Clattering]
-[Imitating gunfire]
-Oh, sorry.
-So if they scissor me in half
with their powerful jaws,
please don't keep me alive.
-Science and the military
working side by side.
-That's where the grasshoppers
go to smoke.
-Ah, finally, the men's room.
I've been looking for it.
-I know what you're thinking,
grasshopper,
did I fire six shots or...
Oh.
-I wasn't scared.
Were you scared?
[Chirping]
-There's that damn kid
on the pogo stick again.
Let's get him.
-Louis, I think this is going
to be the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
I'm Peter Graves.
-Hey, you know,
giant grasshoppers,
you just take it
for granted you can find them,
and then when you want
to them, they disappear!
[Chirping]
-Yes, I'm drunk.
Go! God, leave me alone.
-You know, Chicago
is a 24-hour town.
-Yep!
-Trumpy!
-Hey!
-The von Trapps have escaped!
-Come on!
We got one in here!
Come on!
-And keep quiet.
We just got him down.
-Meanwhile,
in Castle Wrigley...
[Chirping]
-You're dead, Graves.
I've got friends.
This is a dead man
I'm looking at!
-Well, it looks like you were
having a pretty good time
for yourself out in Peoria
last night, eh, Hoppy?
-It's lucky we got one of
the smaller grasshoppers.
-Calm down. This will go easy
on you if you just
give us some names.
-Not too close, Major.
We put that cage up in a hurry,
and I don't know
how strong it is.
-Come on.
How about some grass in here?!
-I was teaching
my engineering class
at the university.
It was safe and secure,
but look at me now.
-I'm not safe and secure.
[Chirping]
-You know, I'm 37 years old,
and all of a sudden,
I realized for the first time
how much
I've taken life for granted.
-Not now.
-I guess that's something you
can't take for granted, Major.
-Ed, how will you knowwhen you've got the right sound?
-Uh, I have no idea.
-He'll tell us.
-How?
-He'll react to it,
and this polygraph
will record his reaction.
-How long will it take?
-It's a matter of
trial and error.
Could take 10 minutes
or 10 hours.
-I think Pete was affected
by that gas.
-Yeah.
-We don't have 10 hours.
-We've got theater tickets.
-They're dropping
that bomb at dawn.
-I hate to ask you this,
but where are your nipples?
-How does this work?
-Well, I've just attached
these wires from the polygraph
to the two copper strips
at the base of the cage.
Now, the locust, like every
other living thing, has...
-Just a little closer.
Come here, just closer.
-...direct ratio to its activityor emotional stimulation.
-Next time, Flatfoot,
you're mine.
-I don't understand.
-Well, in other words, when wehit the correct sound or signal,
the grasshopper
will react to it,
and the polygraph
will record the change.
-Mm-hmm.
-Now, you notice how steady
and regular the movement
of the needle is now?
-Oh, yes.
-Well, when we reproduce
the grasshopper's call,
the lines will become longer
and highly irregular.
-Like a lie-detector test.
-Sit down.
-Well, it's the first time
a grasshopper ever got one.
Now if you'll keep your eye
on the needle for any
unusual jumps or dips...
-Well, we'll just head off.
I got a little surprise
for you guys.
-Oh, goody.
-This is gonna be really fun.
-Boy, goody.
-Will you set up that
big brick wall...
[Machine whirring,
locust chirping]
[Doors thud and creak]
-[Chuckles]
-Okay, Mr. Tom Servo.
Are you ready for this?
-Oh, you bet, Mike.
This movie has given me a great
idea for a stand-up routine.
Now take your seat.
I'm ready.
-Okay. All right.
-Okay, lights, Cambot.
Thank you.
Thank you, everybody.
What a beautiful crowd
tonight, huh?
Say, did you ever notice
the difference
between grasshoppers
and locusts?
[Chuckles]
Well, for one thing,
locusts have shorter antennae
than grasshoppers.
Grasshoppers walking down
the street like,
"Hey, look at me.
I got some big antennae."
[Chuckles] Where a locust
is walking down the street,
it's more like, "Oh, no.
My antennas are so small."
[Laughs]
Smaller antenna,
you see on the lo...
Hey, have you
checked out the ovipositor
on a female grasshopper?
You see, the use them
to drill holes in the grass.
You know what I mean?
They're like, "Oh, I need
to drill a hole.
Hope I brought my ovipositor."
[Laughs]
But female locusts
have short ovipositors,
so they're more like, "Oh, no,
my ovipositors are so small."
[Laughs]
Oh, what else can I tell you
about mys...
Oh, longhorn grasshoppers,
are they something or what?
[Laughs] You know, they come
from the family tettigoniidae.
Am I right?
Ladies, back me up on this one.
Now, you see, locusts,
they're different
from the tettigoniidae,
especially those
Rocky Mountain locusts.
They're known
as melanoplus spretus.
Thank you. Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen!
Tip your waitresses.
Good night.
Thank you very much.
Oh, thank you.
-Wow.
Tom, that --
that really, really...
-Sucked, sucked.
-Oh, no.
It was very good.
It was informative, too.
-Well, gee, thanks.
You know, I was thinking of
doing it on "The Tonight Show."
-Oh, Tom, I mean,
you were good,
but, I mean, you know,
you got to be really,
really good to be
on "The Tonight Show."
-Well, how about
"David Letterman" then?
-Well, they just don't let
anybody on "Letterman."
-How about "Chevy Chase"?
-Hey, there you go.
Send him a tape. I think you gota real shot at it.
-Gee, thanks.
-We'll be right back.
-Thank you.
♪♪
[Chirping]
-Very good.
Very, very good.
-Byron Allen.
-So you in love with me yet?
No, huh?
-I have my rights!
I have my rights!
[Machine whirring,
locust chirping]
-Well, I've just come to see
what you've done
with all the grant money.
Oh, my God!
-Wainwright, you've
had your chance.
Now it's the Air Force's turn.
-Copper strips on bottom
of the cage.
Hello!
-Operator.
Operator, this is
a top-priority call.
Get me General Wagner
at the air base.
-You hear me, Graves?
You're not getting anything
out of me, nothing!
-One moment.
♪ Bah, ba-da-duh da
-I'm getting
"The Piña Colada Song."
-Look, General, the locusts
outside will stay put until
the temperature
reaches 68 degrees.
That's about an hour
and a half from now.
-Oh, this phone
is smooth, sleek...
Uh, hello?
-Wagner?
Chicago has been evacuated.
Unless you receive instructions
to the contrary,
by 0616, that is...
-Oh, call it 8:00.
-That is 90 minutes from now.
-That good for you?
-We'll order your B-52 crew
to deliver the bomb
on the designated target.
-Start with the Shedd Aquarium.
-Repeat the instructions
back to me.
-Yes, I love you, too.
-Correct.
-[Smooches]
-Would you stop questioning
the grasshopper?
-There's no time to fool
with that now.
Major, get a detail of men
up here to move this stuff.
-Look at him.
He's got an hourglass shape.
-Nice!
-Bring some extra grenades.
There's some in my staff car.
There's a new lab set up for youat my new HQ outside the city.
-I can't move now.
-Well, you can't stay here,
not with an atom bomb
hanging over your head.
-I don't have any choice.
-I'm Peter Graves.
-Up to now, we've been using
a filtered signal,
and it hasn't worked,
but it's just possible that
the hearing apparatus
of the locust
can detect harmonic frequencies
above the human range.
Well, to test these frequencies,I need every minute that's left.
If you'll just give me one man
to replace Ms. Aimes...
-I'm staying.
-[Gasps]
-Well, look, this is no time to
be worrying about a big story.
-I'm not worried about a story.
-Look, I just want
to drop my A-bombs.
-Will you please leave before
it's too late?
-No.
-Major?
-Hmm?
-You and a detail of two men
will remain here
with Mr. Wainwright.
-Mm-hmm.
-I will station men
at three observation posts,
one in the suburbs,
one near the Art Institute...
-Mm-hmm.
-...and one top
of the downtown hotel.
-And one on top of me.
-Also, a helicopter will spot
from above.
There will be a getaway car
parked downstairs
at the main entrance.
I suggest you use it by...
-Oh, 8:00, I guess.
-...by 5:45 at the very latest.
If you are successful,
contact me at once
so I can stop the bomb.
-Just a little bowl
of wheat, please!
Oh!
-It's oh-five, um, uh...
-Well, good morning.
You got the Loop here.
It's going to be
a nice day today.
We're going to get bombed.
You probably heard about that.
-They're scraping the grills
at The Billy Goat
at this very moment.
-Mmm.
[Machine whirring]
-I'm a gr -- grasshopper.
That's all I am, honest.
[Whirring continues]
It's "Sweet Lorraine."
-Do I really have to
stay here for this?
-Huh, so, uh,
where's the razzmatazz?
I don't see it, hmm.
-Hm. Nope.
-[As Jack Lemmon] I've got to
have those Glengarry leads.
-Have you ever associated
with crickets?
Have you ever taken part
in a plague?
-No!
-Have you eaten crops in excess
of $1 million?!
-[Sobbing]
-That damn Tandy equipment.
[Machine whirring]
-Folks, as for traffic today,
there's none.
Can't explain it.
[Chuckles]
What do you know?
-Boy, the convention business
just went straight downhill,
didn't it?
-Wow.
Look at that.
[Machine whirring]
-What in the Sam Hill
is he doing?
-I'm not going to admit
my failure.
-Well, it's shaping up to be
a pretty nice day.
Maybe go get some
Christmas shopping done.
Not a lot of competition.
[Machine whirring]
-It's a long
Kathleen Battle aria.
-Well, maybe he's innocent.Maybe they got the wrong hopper.
-Hmm.
-D'oh, I forgot
to turn this thing on.
[Machine whirring]
-[Imitating whirring]
-Hey, look at this.
-He's got high blood pressure.
-I think you've got it!
-This is what it sounds like
when grasshoppers cry.
-That's it, Audrey,
we've got it.
-My jaw jigging...
[Laughing]
-[Screams]
-Whoa.
-Oh.
-Oh, no, not the face!
You took out
a couple thousand eyes!
-Pete, Pete, short,
controlled bursts!
-Hey, I've got it.
We could just shoot them.
-Ah, well, acceptable losses.
-I had to shoot him.
-Well, let's chocolate dip
that grasshopper.
-Get that thing out of here.
-Bug fell and hit his head
against the bars
if anyone asks, right?
-Well, back at it.
I want to polygraph
the doorknob now.
-Emergency Lab to Chicago GHQ.
Emergency Lab to Chicago GHQ.
Come in, General.
Are you there?
-Now listen to me, Wainwright.
-We've found it, General.
We've found the frequency.
-Hmm.
-Good.
Now stand by.
I've got to stop that A-bomb.
I'll get right back to you.
Chicago GHQ to Double B.
Chicago GHQ to Double B, over.
-They're not going to let us
drop the bomb.
Don't answer it.
-This is Double B.
Come in, Chicago GHQ, over.
-Hanson here.
Your mission is canceled.
-Real sorry, boys.
-Return to your base.
Repeat the message, over.
-It's the Commies.
-Mission canceled.
Return to base, over.
-Repeat it again.
-Chicago GHQ to emergency lab.
-Right here.
-The show is yours, Wainwright.
-All right, get that equipment
on the lake in a boat,
and I'll be your pied piper.
-Get me my little green shoes
with the curly toes.
-Oh, I love men
who use fairy-tale imagery.
♪♪
-♪ Dah, da-da-da-da-da-dah,
dah, da-da-da-da-dah ♪
-He just polygraphed
a sandwich.
He needs real help.
-I still don't understand.
Why didn't you put
the oscillator in the boat
in the first place
to send out the call?
Why attract them here?
-Because we'd never
get them all.
-Oh.
-Here, look.
-"Dilbert" is a scream today.
-Here we are in downtown
Chicago near the lake.
-Mm-hmm.
-Now, the locusts are scattered
all through the suburbs
and on the South Side.
-Hmm.
-We'll send out the call
from here.
-Yeah, but that's going
to attract them to us,
not into the water.
-Shut up.
-First of all, it's imperative
that every last one
of the locusts hear the call.
Now, in order to do that,
we've got to get
our amplifier speaker
at the highest possible point
to get maximum range.
Now we've got ours on the roof
of this building,
which is one of the tallest
in Chicago.
Now, once we get them here...
-Mm-hmm.
-I see.
Then the boat will take over.
-Exactly.
Once we have them in the heart
of the Loop, near our location,
they'll be within range
of the amplifier on the boat.
Now, we'll then radio
our oscillator signal
out to the boat,
and they, in turn,
will rebroadcast it
over their amplifier...
-You getting this?
-...attracting the locusts
to them and into the lake.
-We hope.
-You see?
That's what you do so well.
You cut me down.
-Will you check and see
about the temperature?
-I know a scientist
who needs a back rub.
-How can we be sure, sir?
-Hmm?
What do you mean?
-How can you know
that we'll get them all?
-Well, that's where
our observation posts
and the helicopter come in.
From their reports, we'll know
the exact location
of the locusts at all times
and if it's working.
-It's 70 degrees, Ed.
-Cooler near the lake.
-They're probably starting
to move.
-Emergency lab
to all observation posts.
Emergency lab to all
observation posts.
Report in, over.
-I'm hiding from a lion.
-Observation post number two
to emergency lab, over.
-It's got these women
scared stiff.
-What is your location?
Over.
-I'm situated in a store
across from the Art Institute
on Michigan Boulevard.
-Olga bras are on sale.
-Nothing in sight, out.
-Observation post number three
to emergency lab.
-I'm on the roof
of the Drayton Hotel.
-I see a huge
swirling crown rose.
-No sign of
grasshoppers in this area,
but the South Side's
getting some action.
-Wow.
-Out.
♪♪
-Emergency Lab to
observation post one.
Emergency Lab to
You did not report in.
What's your location, post one?
-Nothing going on here.
-This is observation
post number one.
I'm right in the middle of them!
I'm just south of 73rd
and South Shore Drive, out.
-Jimmy Fralic's mom says
I can stay for dinner.
-Emergency Lab
to helicopter, over.
-The name is Jeffrey.
I happen to be ina helicopter.
-Emergency lab,
the locusts are active
on the South Side of Chicago.
As yet, there are none
in the downtown area, out.
-Can you read me,
emergency lab?
Over.
-Yes, we can read you fine,
General.
Are you all set?
Over.
-Now, we're not
quite ready yet.
-Dummy here can't
fix the radio.
-I need you to hold off
a few more minutes.
-Come on.
-Over.
-I think we better start now,
General.
If they should change
their direction and start
moving away from Chicago,
we may not get them all, over.
-I don't like your starting
until we're completely ready.
This boat has to draw them
away from you
in a split second's notice.
-Ah, righty tighty.
-Over.
-I'd like to start, sir.
-Then go ahead.
-Baby.
-When I say, "Frog,"
that guy jumps.
-All right, I'm going to
polygraph my tie.
-Yes, sir?
-Is that the wire that leads
to the speaker on the roof?
-Sure.
-Well, plug it
into the amplifier, will you?
-Yes, sir.
-[Imitates electricity]
Aaaah!
[High-pitched whirring]
-All right! Playing Tull
out the window, man.
-Whoo!
-When Brian Eno ruled Chicago.
[High-pitched whirring]
I don't remember that.
-Post number one
to emergency lab.
The locusts are leaving
this section.
They're heading towards
Chicago's downtown.
-If they wanted to rev up
the grasshoppers,
they just should've
played some Marvin Gaye.
-Yeah.
-Helicopter to emergency lab.
-I'm still Paul Frees.
-The locusts are moving
on the downtown area.
-They're radically altering
their size
depending on your perspective.
-So does this, uh, bus, uh,
go all the way to...
-Just get on the bus!
-Oh.
-We've got to get
organized, Hoppy!
-Observation post number three
to emergency lab.
The locusts are everywhere.
-Yep, over there, too,
everywhere pretty much.
-They're moving
towards your location.
I repeat, the locusts
are moving toward
the emergency lab.
-They've gotten ahold
of firearms, and they're drunk.
-Michigan Boulevard
is filled with them!
They're everywhere!
-They're on a shopping rampage!
-Emergency lab to boat.
Emergency lab to boat.
It's working, General.
It's working.
-You never take me anywhere.
-I heard the reports.
[High-pitched whirring]
[Locusts chirping]
-Wow, would you look at that?
They dyed the river green.
-That Dick Daley.
-We're in the famous
Loop now, Harry.
-Wonder why they call it that.
-Ha! Wacker!
Look at that.
-Ha!
-Wacker.
[Locusts chirping]
-I'm blowing the light.
This is bogus.
-Yep.
-I'm right behind
you here, okay?
[Laughter]
-Oh, man.
-Well, looks good, everybody.
I think we're okay,
in pretty good shape.
Nothing to worry about.
Intelligent,
sophisticated equipment.
I think -- Aaaah!
-[Man screaming]
-That's what I said.
-You want to take over
that watch post, honey?
-Are you as turned on as I am?
-Here they come.
They're coming down the street.
-Get the funniest looks
from everyone they meet.
-What do you want?!
[Locusts chirping]
-They're climbing the building.
-Oh, and their feet are dirty.
-That's a postcard!
♪♪
-Whoa, hey, watch it.
You're stepping off
the building there.
[Locusts chirping]
[Gunfire]
-Carry out our work!
-Aaah!
-Wainwright to boat.
Wainwright to boat.
Come in, please.
Come in.
-What boat?
-Come in, Wainwright.
-How soon are you ready?
-We're ready as soon
as we get clearance
from the observation posts.
I'll check them immediately.
Out.
-As soon as Marconi
here is ready.
-Boat to helicopter.
-They're still going in, sir,
but it'll be a while before
they all reach
the downtown section.
-Wainwright?
-What?
-You'll have to hold out
a bit longer.
All the locusts haven't reached
the downtown area yet.
[Gunfire]-Excuse me!
I'm on the phone here.
-All right. We'll try.
-I might as well do it myself.
-Want some? Aah!
-Not again! What a day!
-Save yourself, Tony!
-Top of
the Wrigley Building, Ma!
-It's not quite the top.
-We can't hold on much longer!
-Look, I want to talk.
I want to live. I -- Aaah!
-Watch it, Carl! Oh.
Oh, thank goodness.
-Boat to observation posts.
-Well, we're not going
to get this going.
-Over.
-Post number one.
-Jimmy's mom is serving
meat loaf.
-Post number two.
All clear, sir.
-Helicopter reporting.
-This guy is crazy up there!
-Oh, the third time!
How stupid am I?
-Say goodbye to my 10,000 kids!
[Locusts chirping]
-Hey, I'm just going
to the observation deck.
Aaah!
-Lost my chops.
-Whenever you're ready,
General!
-Then let's have it.
-Okay, go ahead, Audrey.
-There.
-Throw the switch.
[High-pitched whirring]-Oh, Jiminy, shut that off!
[High-pitched whirring]
[Gunfire]
-Geez, I'm out of here.
-I know when I'm not wanted.
Don't shoot. Goodbye.
I'm out of here.
[Locusts chirping]
-You guys feel as silly
as I do?
Oh, Oak Street Beach.
-Mm-hmm.
-Get off the postcard! They're
gonna blow the postcard!
-You've been distant lately.
-Not now.
-Let's spit on them.
-Helicopter to boat.
General, they're responding.
They're responding!
They're swarming
toward the water!
-Don't linger on that shot.
-They're going into the water.
-Whew.
-It's a trick!
It's got to be a trick!
There can't be that many lady
grasshoppers in Lake Michigan.
-Wow, and Chicago thought
the alewives smelled bad.
Whoo!
-Well, let's see
what this baby can do.
Let her rip, Private.
-Hit it!
[Imitates boat engine]
-Head for shore.
-Well, we just spent
the goofiest week
of our entire lives.
-It's gonna be tough for them.
All they ever really shared
were the grasshoppers.
-Yeah.
-This guy caused
the whole thing.
He's got to be doing hard time
in Joliet right now.
-Nah, the grasshoppers
ate Joliet.
-Oh.
-Hey, hey,
slow down there, Romeo.
Where's your other hand?
-♪ Hey, Mr. Arnstein
♪ Here I am
♪♪
[Doors thud and creak]
-Hey, Tom.
-Y-y-y-y-y-yes?
-Is this the first movie
with grasshoppers?
-You know, I think it is.
I can't remember ever seeing
a single grasshopper.
-And then today,
nothing but grasshoppers.
-Wow, weird.
-Now, come on.
There had to have been one
or two grasshoppers.
-Nope.
-No, siree, zip.
-That is weird.
That is weird.
You know, maybe we should
read a postcard.
-Hey!
-Good idea.
-Okay, we got this one here
from Kent and Amy Hakaida.
Put that up on
still store there, Cambot.
They say, "As members of
the Kim Cattrall Fan Club"...
Crow, Kim Cattrall!
-Wow!
-Oh, yes, yes!
-"We wondered if you were
going to view
Oliver Stone's 'Wild Palms.'"
-Uh...
-Has that been on yet?
-No.
I don't think that it...
-Ew.
-"Well, got to go.
The fathers and friends
are going at it
in the swimming p -- pool."
-Wow!
-Whoa!
-Whoo-hoo!
-Wow.
That is salty.
-Yowch.
-You know, the great thing
about these postcards people
send in, though,
they double as great
Bert I. Gordon special effects.
This is great, Cambot.
-Hey, cool!
-Check this out.
-Okay.
-Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no!
-Grasshoppers are attacking
the beach on Andicuri, Aruba!
No!
-Aaah!
-Help!
-Aaaah!
Oh, that's funny. Hey.
I got one. I got one here.
Oh, no. The grasshoppers,
aaah, they're attacking
The Beatles!
-Oh!
-Ah!
-Defend Ringo at all costs.
-Oh, they're attacking me.
-Gah! Aaah!
-Oh, look at this. Oh!
Grasshoppers, they don't care.
Now, they're going for
the Village of the Spires
in Oldenburg, Indiana.
-Why?
-Aaaah!
-Grasshoppers, have you
no decency?
-Oh, oh!
-Oh, no!
Grasshoppers have scaled
to the very top
of Earl "Fatha" Hines.
-Oh, watch the hands!
Oh!
-[As Peter Graves] We are
witnessing a time when
the beasts have reclaimed
Earl "Fatha" Hines.
-Crow!
-I'm Peter Graves.
-I'm done.
-I'll say.
-Back to you.
-Huh?
-Oh.
-Be careful.
-Oh, maybe we --
we should go back down there.
Remember what happened
last time?
-Thank you, sirs.
-Ooh!
-Keep your hands up, Frank.
-Uh, ah!
Mike, uh, got us in the middle
of our daily routine.
What's that they say
about boxing, Frank?
-It's the only real sport.
It's the only honest sport!
It's the sport of men!
-Absolutely right.
Uh, grab yourself
a beer and, uh,
grab me one, too,
fellow fighter.
-Okay. Because we're men!
We are men!
-Yes. You've made
your point, Frank.
-We're men!
-Yes, Frank.
Oh! Ugh!
You want a piece of me?
Come on. Come on. Huh?
Huh?
[Grunting]
Oh! Oh! Ah!
Oh, Frank, Frank, Frank,
please, please, enough.
I have to get the button.
Ooh!
-[Chuckles]
-[Grunts]
♪♪
-All right, men.
Into the woods.